<databaseChangeLog xmlns='http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog'
                   xmlns:xsi='http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance'
                   xsi:schemaLocation='http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog
    http://www.liquibase.org/xml/ns/dbchangelog/dbchangelog-3.6.xsd'>


    <changeSet author="marek.nalepka" id="0.2.0010.0010">
        <sql>
            ALTER TABLE `Weapon`
            MODIFY COLUMN `range` TEXT;

            ALTER TABLE `Weapon`
            MODIFY COLUMN `shots` TEXT;

            ALTER TABLE `Weapon`
            MODIFY COLUMN `penetration` TEXT;

            INSERT INTO Weapon
            VALUES
            (1, 'Rifle', 24, 1, 0),
            (2, 'Pistol', 6, 1, 0),
            (3, 'Submachine gun', 12, 2, 0),
            (4, 'Automatic Rifle', 30, 2, 0),
            (5, 'Assault Rifle', 18, 2, 0),
            (6, 'Light machine gun', 36, 4, 0),
            (7, 'Medium machine gun', 36, 5, 0),
            (8, 'Heavy machine gun', 36, 3, 1),
            (9, 'Light automatic cannon', 48, 2, 2),
            (10, 'Heavy automatic cannon', 72, 2, 3),
            (11, 'PIAT', 12, 1, 5),
            (12, 'Bazooka', 24, 1, 5),
            (13, 'Panzerschreck', 24, 1, 6),
            (14, 'Panzerfaust', 12, 1, 6),
            (15, 'Light AT gun', 48, 1, 4),
            (16, 'Medium AT gun', 60, 1, 5),
            (17, 'Heavy AT gun', 72, 1, 6),
            (18, 'Super-heavy AT gun', 84, 1, 7),
            (19, 'Flamethrower (infantry)', 6, 'D6', 3),
            (20, 'Flamethrower (vehicle)', 12, 'D6+1', 3),
            (21, 'Light mortar', '12-24', 1, 'HE'),
            (22, 'Medium mortar',  '12-60', 1, 'HE'),
            (23, 'Heavy mortar', '12-72', 1, 'HE'),
            (24, 'Light howitzer', '48 (or 24-60)', 1, 'HE'),
            (25, 'Medium howitzer', '60 (or 30-72)', 1, 'HE'),
            (26, 'Heavy howitzer', '72 (or 36-84)', 1, 'HE');

            INSERT INTO Rule
            VALUES
            (1, 'Assault', 'This weapon suffers no penalty to hit when moving and shooting. In addition, infantry models armed with an assault weapon count as tough fighters. When a tough fighter scores a casualty in close quarters against infantry or artillery, it can immediately make a second damage roll.', 'Core Rulebook', 90),
            (2, 'Team', 'A Team weapon shoots at full effectiveness so long as there are at least two men to serve it. If only one man remains then the weapon suffers a -1 to hit penalty, and -1 penalty to its morale. For squad-based team weapons, loader must remain within 1" or weapon suffers the -1 to-hit penalty.', 'Core Rulebook', 99),
            (3, 'Fixed', 'When given Advance order, fixed weapons can rotate on the spot suffering a -1 to-hit penalty. Non-artillery Fixed can move normal 12" when given Run order.', 'Core Rulebook', 90),
            (4, 'HE(1")', 'PEN: +1, PIN: D2 (D3 if in building) - Infantry and artillery can go down to halve the hits taken', 'Core Rulebook', 92),
            (5, 'HE(2")', 'PEN: +2, PIN: D3 (D6 if in building) - Infantry and artillery can go down to halve the hits taken', 'Core Rulebook', 92),
            (6, 'HE(3")', 'PEN: +3, PIN: D3 (2D6 if in building) - Infantry and artillery can go down to halve the hits taken', 'Core Rulebook', 92),
            (7, 'HE(4")', 'PEN: +4, PIN: D6 (3D6 if in building) - Infantry and artillery can go down to halve the hits taken', 'Core Rulebook', 92),
            (8, 'Shaped Charge' , 'Never suffer the -1 penetration modifier for firing at long range.', 'Core Rulebook', 99),
            (9, 'One-shot', 'This is a disposable weapon that can be fired only once per game. Once fired replace the model with another model that does not carry the disposable weapon', 'Core Rulebook', 99),
            (10, 'Flamethrower' , 'Flamethrowers never suffer to-hit penalties for cover or Down. Hits multiplied into D6 (D6+1 for vehicle flamethrower). Always hits top armour. No -1 PEN for long range. Gun shield and extra protection rules do not apply. Units hit take D3+1 pins and must always check morale (if fail, then destroyed). Flamethrower rolls D6 - on 1 it runs out of fuel. When rolling to damage vehicle with flamerthrower, add +1 to damage effects chart. ', 'Core Rulebook', 91),
            (11, 'Indirect Fire', 'Hit on 6, -1 each turn if both target and shooter did not move', 'Core Rulebook', 96),
            (12, 'Howitzer', 'Can either shoot directly at a target drawing its line of fire over open sights in the normal way, or it can shoot indirect fire. When using indirect fire, a howitzer has a minimum range; when firing over open sights it has no minimum range.', 'Core Rulebook', 96);
        </sql>
    </changeSet>
</databaseChangeLog>